Perls Galleries
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Perls Galleries records
1937-1997
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
Perls Galleries
79.7 linear feet
The records of the Perls Galleries measure 79.7 linear feet and date from 1937 to 1997. Founded by Klaus Perls in 1937 and operating until 1997, the gallery dealt primarily in modern French art and the artwork of Alexander Calder. Found within the records are extensive correspondence (circa 44 linear feet) with artists, dealers, galleries, museums, and collectors; photographs and negatives of inventory and other artwork; exhibition files, scattered financial records; and exhibition catalogs and clippings.
Provenance
The records were donated in 1997 by Douglas Mayhew, associate and legal representive of Klaus G. and Amelia B. Perls.
Related Material
Among the resources relating to the Perls Galleries in the Archives of American Art is an oral history interview with Klaus Perls done by Mona Hadler on January 19, 1993.
Restrictions on Access
Use of original papers requires an appointment.
Historical Note
Klaus Perls (b. 1912, d. 2008) formally opened Perls Galleries in New York in 1937, and ran it with his wife Amelia until its closing in 1997. The gallery dealt in contemporary French artists of the School of Paris, such as Georges Braque and Pablo Picasso, but also acted as the primary representative of Alexander Calder beginning in 1954. In the 1970s Mr. Perls developed an interest in art from Benin and built an important collection of African sculpture, some of which was later donated to the Metropolitan Museum of Art. Amelia Perls died in 2002, and Klaus Perls died in 2008.
Klaus Perls was born in 1912 in Berlin in a house Mies van der Rohe designed for his parents, who owned an art gallery specializing in Impressionists, post-Impressionists, Old Master paintings, Pablo Picasso, Georges Braque, and African sculpture. Perls studied Art History in Hamburg and Munich but completed his PhD in Basel, Switzerland in 1933 after the Nazi government stopped awarding degrees to Jews. His dissertation covered the complete works of 15th-century French painter Jean Fouquet.
Before moving to New York in 1935, Perls worked for his mother, Kaethe Perls, in her Paris gallery that she opened in 1932 after splitting up with Klaus' father Hugo. He spent his first two years in New York selling paintings through other art dealers, primarily paintings shipped or recommended to him by his mother from Paris that were not selling well in the Depression-era French art market. These were primarily the work of Maurice Utrillo, Marie Laurencin, Raoul Dufy and Maurice de Vlaminck. In 1937 he formally established his own gallery, the Perls Galleries, on East 58th Street and continued to specialize in French and European contemporary art. Around the same time, his older brother Frank opened a gallery in Beverly Hills, California.
Klaus Perls was familiar with other New York dealers specializing in modern European art such as Valentine Dudensing and Pierre Matisse, but he tried to distinguish himself by catering to young collectors. When the war restricted the international art trade and his mother was forced to flee France during the Occupation, Perls began dealing in contemporary American artists such as Darrel Austin and Karl Priebe.
Perls married Amelia Blumenthal, fondly known as "Dolly," in 1940, and she became his business partner.
After the war, the international art market exploded, and the Perls made frequent buying trips to Europe. The Perls Galleries continued to sell primarily contemporary French art and gained an early reputation as a staunch defender of modern art by European artists such as Picasso, Modigliani, Braque, Léger, Soutine and Pascin. Perls prepared catalogues raisonnés on Soutine and Pascin.
Klaus Perls was one of the founding members of the Art Dealer's Association, whose initial mission was to clean up the reputation of the art market following a series scandals involving fake antiquities that flourished in the 1960's. Perls was the Association's second president, after Pierre Matisse.
In 1954 Perls Galleries moved to 1016 Madison Avenue, a building that served as both gallery and home for the Perls. The same year Perls became Alexander Calder's dealer after the death of Calder's previous dealer, Curt Valentin. Perls explained his inclusion of Calder, a rare American among his stable of European artists, by saying that Calder's roots lay in France and that Calder bridged Europe and America the way Perls felt he did himself. In 1970, Calder designed the terrazzo sidewalk in front of the gallery and often resided in the Perls' home during long visits to New York City. Perls Galleries later handled Calder's estate and functioned as a quasi-archives of Calder's works, holding more than 7,000 negatives depicting Calder's art and preparing a Calder catalogue raisonné.
Klaus was named as a third-party defendant in the 1969 World War II looted art case Menzel v. List. When Erna Menzel sued Albert List for ownership of a Chagall painting confiscated from Menzel by the Nazis, List in turn sued Perls, who had sold him the painting in 1955, having purchased it himself from a Paris art dealer. The court awarded the Chagall painting to Menzel and ordered Perls to pay List the appreciated value of the painting.
Perls began building an important collection of African artwork and fell in love with art from Benin in the 1970's. In 1991 he donated more than 150 pieces of royal art from Benin to the Metropolitan Museum of Art.
The Perls closed their gallery in 1997; Amelia Perls died in 2002, and Klaus Perls died in 2008.
Scope and Content Note
The records of the Perls Galleries measure 79.7 linear feet and date from 1937 to 1997. Founded by Klaus Perls in 1937 and operating until 1997, the gallery dealt primarily in modern French art and the artwork of Alexander Calder. Found within the records are extensive correspondence (circa 44 linear feet) with artists, dealers, galleries, museums, and collectors; photographs and negatives of inventory and other artwork; exhibition files, scattered financial records; and exhibition catalogs and clippings.
Correspondence primarily discusses sales (and includes invoices), loans, and exhibitions, as well as more routine activities such as gallery maintenance, the printing of exhibition catalogs and letterhead, and the shipment, framing, or restoration of artwork. Many letters enclose photographs, negatives, or slides of artwork, and clippings. A few letters contain oversize architectural or engineering drawings, and a small handful of letters are illustrated.
Correspondents include artists such as Darrell Austin, Joan Miró, Pablo Picasso, and Karl Priebe; galleries such as the Corcoran Gallery, Fujikawa Galleries, Galerie Maeght, and the Pierre Matisse Gallery; museums such as the Art Institute of Chicago, the Museum of Modern Art, the National Gallery of Art, and the Whitney Museum of Modern Art; collectors such as Morris and Gwendolyn Cafritz, Adelaide de Ménil, Valentine Dudensing, and Henry Ford, II; and celebrity clients such as Greta Garbo, Alfred Hitchcock, Henry and Clare Booth Luce, and Barbra Streisand.
The records contain nearly thirty-two linear feet of photographs and negatives. Photographs are of artists and the inventory of the gallery's artwork. Additional photographs represent artwork either by artists not represented by the gallery or not included in the gallery's inventory. Most of the photographs are black and white. Over fifteen linear feet of negatives are of gallery stock. Photographs are also found in the exhibition files.
There is a relatively small amount of records relating to exhibitions, loans, and sales. Found are exhibition lists, schedules, invitations and announcements, photographs of exhibition installations, press releases, and records of loans to other institutions and galleries. Sales records include artist lists, inventory lists, invoices, pick up and delivery receipts, and price lists.
Printed materials include a large number of clippings and an incomplete run of catalogs from Perls Galleries exhibitions between 1939 and 1980.
The collection also includes ten original pencil drawings from John Canaday's series entitled My Beautiful Girls and a reproduction of eight drawings from the same series
Arrangement
The collection is arranged as 7 series:
Series 1: Correspondence, 1937-1995 (Boxes 1-44, OV 81-83; 43.6 linear feet)
Series 2: Negatives, circa 1937-1995 (Boxes 44-59; 15.7 linear feet)
Series 3: Photographs, circa 1937-1995 (Boxes 60-75, OV 84; 16.1 linear feet)
Series 4: Exhibition, Loan, and Sales Records, 1937-1995 (Boxes 76-78; 2.1 linear feet)
Series 5: Clippings Files, 1943-1989 (Box 78; 0.5 linear feet)
Series 6: Exhibition Catalogs, 1939-1980 (Boxes 78-79; 1.4 linear feet)
Series 7: Drawings by John Canaday, circa 1967-1972 (Box 80; 0.3 linear feet)
Names and Subject Terms
This collection is indexed in the online catalog of the Archives of American Art under the following terms:
Subjects:
Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976
Subjects-Topical:
Art, Modern
Types of Materials:
Drawings; Illustrated letters; Photographs
Names:
Austin, Darrel, 1907-; Cafritz, Gwendolyn; Cafritz, Morris, 1886?-1964; Canaday, John, 1907-; De Menil, Adelaide; Dudensing, F. Valentine, 1901-circa 1960; Ford, Henry, 1917-1987; Garbo, Greta, 1905-1990; Hitchcock, Alfred, 1899-; Luce, Henry, III, 1925-2005; Luce, Clare Boothe, 1903-1987; Miró, Joan, 1893-; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973; Priebe, Karl J., 1914-1976; Streisand, Barbra; Art Institute of Chicago; Fujikawa Gallery; Galerie Maeght; James Corcoran Gallery; Museum of Modern Art -- New York, N.Y.; National Gallery of Art -- U.S.; Pierre Matisse Gallery -- New York, N.Y.; Whitney Museum of American Art
Series Descriptions/Container Listing
- Correspondence, 1937-1995, Series 1:; (Boxes 1-44, OV 81-83; 43.6 linear feet)
  This series consists of original incoming correspondence and duplicate copies of outgoing correspondence documenting gallery exhibits, loans, sales, and routine maintenance activities. Correspondence is with artists, galleries, museums, collectors, dealers, publications, and staff while the Perls traveled. Also found is correspondence concerning routine business affairs such as framing, restoration, and shipping; gallery-related services such as locksmiths and window and drapery cleaners; and business-related services such as accounting, taxes, and legal representation. A handful of project files relating to the commission or installation of Calder sculptures in public spaces follows the Calder correspondence file.
  Significant correspondents include artists Darrell Austin, Joan Miró, Pablo Picasso, and Karl Priebe; galleries such as the Corcoran Gallery, Fujikawa Galleries, Galerie Maeght, and the Pierre Matisse Gallery; museums such as the Art Institute of Chicago, the Museum of Modern Art, the National Gallery of Art, and the Whitney Museum of Modern Art; collectors such as Morris and Gwendolyn Cafritz, Adelaide de Ménil, Valentine Dudensing, and Henry Ford, II; and celebrity clients such as Greta Garbo, Alfred Hitchcock, Henry and Clare Booth Luce, and Barbra Streisand.
  Many letters enclose photographs, negatives, or slides of artwork and contain requests for the artwork to be identified, authenticated, or appraised. Additional letters enclose clippings mentioning Perls or the gallery, or discussing artists collected by Perls, notable art world figures or trends, or exhibitions at Perls Galleries or other galleries including artwork loaned by Perls Galleries. A few letters include oversize architectural or engineering drawings, usually relating to the installation of Calder stabiles.
  A small handful of letters from Carol Blanchard, Robert and Elodie Osborn, and Karl Priebe are illustrated, and original artwork can be found in the Adelaide Milton de Groot file.
  Many of the correspondence files include copies of invoices for artwork sold and occasional provenance information, useful to supplement the relatively small amount of sales records in the collection.
  Two color photographs of Calder painting one of his sculptures can be found in the Marcel Fleiss file, and a black and white photograph of Calder standing in front of the terrazzo sidewalk he designed for the Perls Galleries entrance can be found in the Newsweek Magazine file.
  Court records and attorney correspondence regarding the 1969 World War II looted art case Menzel v. List can be found in the Ralph F. Colin, Allan D. Emil, and Albert A. List files.
  Correspondence is arranged alphabetically by correspondent and thereunder approximately in reverse chronological order. Each alphabetical section is completed by miscellaneous files containing correspondence with individuals and organizations, also arrange alphabetically, with whom Perls Galleries exchanged fewer than five letters.
  Many of the records in this series are brittle and require careful handling. Many of the records alphabetized under the letter G have suffered from previous water damage.
  - A. Lipshitz, 1944-1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - A. Steinman Plumbing and Heating Corp., 1967-1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - ACA Galleries, 1970-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - A. L. Stone Displays, 1968-1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Abady, Edward, 1982-1991 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Abbeville Press, 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Abeles, Anne, 1951-1960, 1967, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Abner Schram Ltd., 1984-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Abramson, Herbert, 1994-1995 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Acampora, Julian, 1941-1952 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Acquavella Galleries, Inc., 1968-1976, 1987-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Address Lists1943-1954, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Akademie der Künste, Berlin, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Albert Roullier Art Galleries, 1941-1946 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Albert White Gallery, 1971, 1977-1978 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Albright-Knox Gallery, 1981-1994 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Albright-Knox Gallery, 1972-1977 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Albright-Knox Gallery, 1966-1971 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Albright-Knox Gallery, 1960-1965 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Albright-Knox Gallery, 1945-1950, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Albright-Knox Gallery, 1940-1944 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Aldis Browne Fine Arts, 1981-1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Alexander, Cris, 1945-1946 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Alexander Iolas Gallery, 1942-1949, 1960, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Alexandre Rabow Galleries, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Alex Reid & Lefevre, Ltd., 1977-1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Alex Reid & Lefevre, Ltd., 1954-1971 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Ali Elai, 1988-1995 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Allen, Edna, 1963, 1977-1981 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Allen Memorial Art Museum, 1942-1949, 1957-1958, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - All-Over Locksmiths, Inc., 1958, 1968, 1974, 1981-1992 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Alsdorf, Mr. and Mrs. James, 1968-1978, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Alsdorf, Mr. and Mrs. James, 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Alsdorf, Mr. and Mrs. James, 1955-1957 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Alsdorf, Mr. and Mrs. James, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - The Alumnae Association of Sarah Lawrence College, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Ambler, Philip, 1952-1959, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - The American Academy of Arts and Letters, 1968-1978 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - The American Federation of Arts, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - The American Federation of Arts, 1962-1985 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - The American Federation of Arts, 1947-1961 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - The American Federation of Arts, 1937-1946 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - American Friends of the Hebrew University, 1957-1970 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - American Institute of Architects, 1961-1968 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - The American University, 1949, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Amon Carter Museum, 1963, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Amsterdam, Harvey, 1972-1980 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Anderson, Harry, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - André Emmerich Gallery, 1984-1994 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - André Emmerich Gallery, 1980-1983 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - André Emmerich Gallery, 1975-1979 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - André Emmerich Gallery, 1963-1974 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Andreoli, Thomas, 1982-1995 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Andrew Crispo Gallery, 1969-1984 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Anglim, Paule, 1977-1991 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Anglim, Paule, 1971-1976 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Annely Juda Fine Art, 1971-1972, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Annis, Milton, 1945-1957 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Aoyama Art Salon, Ltd., 1987 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Aram Gallery, 1940, 1946-1948 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Arango, Placido, 1978-1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Archbold, John, 1973-1978 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Archipenko, Alexander, 1960-1963 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Archipenko, Alexander, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Archipenko, Frances, 1968-1981, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Archipenko, Frances, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Architectural Art Services, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Archives of American Art, 1964-1991 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Arkansas Arts Center, 1961-1962, 1986-1988 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Arnold, Stanley, 1958-1960, 1969-1973, 1981, 1986 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Aronson, Cyril, 1948-1949 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Aronson, Cyril, 1946-1947 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Art in America, 1941-1947, 1953-1969, 1974-1977, 1984-1988 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Art Association of Indianapolis, 1959-1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Art Association of Indianapolis, 1942-1952 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - The Art Association of Newport, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - The Art Digest, 1937-1950 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Art Friend Association, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - The Art Gallery, 1957-1959, 1965-1975 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Art Gallery of Ontario, 1974-1975, 1981-1984 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - The Art Gallery of Toronto, 1947, 1954-1965, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - The Art Gallery of Western Australia, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - The Art Institute of Chicago, 1971-1979, 1988, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - The Art Institute of Chicago, 1963-1970 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - The Art Institute of Chicago, 1953-1962 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - The Art Institute of Chicago, 1947-1952 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - The Art Institute of Chicago, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - The Art Institute of Zanesville, OH, 1944-1945 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Art International, 1957-1973 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Art Life Ltd., 1987-1994 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Art Life Ltd., 1984-1986 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Art Museum of South Texas, 1968, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Art News, 1937-1957, 1969, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Arthur Lénars & Cie, 1950-1951, 1960, 1965, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Arthur Tooth & Sons, Ltd., 1947-1965 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - The Arts Club of Chicago, 1955-1977 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - The Arts Club of Chicago, 1940-1951 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - The Arts Council of Great Britain, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - The Arts Council of Great Britain, 1962-1981 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - The Arts and Crafts Gallery of New Orleans, 1945-1949 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Arts Magazine, 1956-1977 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Askin, Arnold, 1963-1968, 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Associated American Artists Galleries, 1945-1954 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Association for Mentall Ill Children, 1969, (see also Bakwin, Ruth) (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Atlanta Art Association, 1951-1960 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Auchinloss, Bayard, 1954-1958, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Ault, Lee, 1947-1982 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Ault, Lee, 1937-1946 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Ausstellungsleitung Haus der Kunst München E. V., 1959-1969, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1964-1966, 1981-1982, 1991 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1962-1963 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1960-1961 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1956-1957 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1954-1955 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1945-1946 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Austin, Darrell, 1942-1944 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Austin, Darrell - Invoices, 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Austin, Darrell - Invoices, 1956-1958 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Austin, Darrell - Invoices, 1953-1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Austin, Darrell - Invoices, 1950-1952 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Austin, Darrell - Invoices, 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Austin, Darrell - Invoices, 1944-1946 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Austin, Darrell - Invoices, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Austin, Darrell - Invoices, 1940-1941 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Australian National Gallery, 1982-1990 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Avnet, Lester, 1964-1971 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Aydelotte, A. L., 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous A, circa 1937-1995, (22 folders) (Box 3, Folder 25-46)
  - B. C. Holland Gallery, 1964-1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Baal-Teshuva, Jacob, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Babath, Arthur C., 1956-1961, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bacri, Jacques, 1943-1953 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Baer, Arthur, 1964-1967, 1975, 1980-1989 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Baker, Doris, 1954, 1962-1965 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Bakwin, Ruth, 1954-1969, 1978-1982, 1993, (see also Association for Mentally Ill Children) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Balstad, Blanche, 1976, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Baltimore Museum of Art, 1969-1973, 1983-1984, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - The Baltimore Museum of Art, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - The Baltimore Museum of Art, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - The Baltimore Museum of Art, 1963-1965 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - The Baltimore Museum of Art, 1940, 1946, 1954-1962 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Barbee, Stanley N., 1940-1958 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Bareiss, Walter, 1952-1956 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Barish, Keith, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Barlow, Sydney R., 1962-1968 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - The Barnes Foundation, 1948-1961, 1973-1978 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Barrett, Altina, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Barsky, Mr. and Mrs. Arthur J., 1942-1945, 1950, 1994-1995 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Bartholdy, Edith Mendelssohn, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Bartlett, David M., 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Bartlett, F. Lewis, 1959-1965 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Bartlett, F. W., 1951-1955, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Bass, Perry R., 1963, 1980-1994 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Bass, Sid R., 1968-1973, 1982-1993 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Bassett, Florence Knoll, 1972-1981, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Bassin, Doreen, 1974, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Baum, Jane, 1965-1967 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Baumgarten, Marlene, 1968-1979, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Beadleston, William, 1976-1977, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Bear, Willard C., 1955-1959, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Beardsley, Walter R., 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Beaudan, Jacques, 1973-1978, 1981-1991 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Beilin, Howard C., 1967-1975, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Bélien, Henri, 1952-1954 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Bell, Lionel, 1967-1979, 1987-1990 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Bellier, Jean-Claude, 1970-1992 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Beloit College, 1951-1954 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Ben-Avi, Mrs. A., 1964-1978, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Benedict, Curt, 1937, 1946-1947 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Benefit Events, 1965-1969, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Benenson, Charles, 1961-1970 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Benenson, Thomas Hartley, 1968-1969, 1975, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Bérè Pierre, 1962-1967, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Berg, Anthony, 1977, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Berggruen, Heinz, 1973-1985 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Berggruen, Heinz, 1966-1972 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Berggruen, Heinz, 1960-1965 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Berggruen, Heinz, 1954-1959 (Box 4, Folder 50)